Boston, Hartford And Erie Railroad Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Boston, Hartford and Erie Railroad Collection.
1863-1885.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Unknown.
4.25 linear feet.
The Railroad was chartered in May 1863 and reorganized in 1873 as the New York and New England Railroad Company.
MSS19920007
History
The Boston, Hartford and Erie Railroad was chartered in May 1863 and reorganized in 1873 as the New York and New England Railroad Company.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, financial and legal records primarily concerning the railroad's bankruptcy prior to 1873.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to New England railroads. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
Boston, Hartford, and Erie Railroad Company.
Subjects:
Railroads--New England.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Maps.; Legal Records.; Financial Records.
Occupations:
Unknown.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Collection was purchased in 1992.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Collection, 1863-1885
  - “Progress of the Work”, 1869 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Central Car Company—Stock resolution, 1885 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1867-1873 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1874-1875 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1876-1878 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Legal records, undated, 1863-1869 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Legal records, 1870 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Legal records, 1871-1872 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Legal records, 1873 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Legal records, 1874-1878 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Financial records, 1867-1875 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Map, undated (Box OS)
  - Notes and memoranda, undated (Box 1:, Folder 12)